Guide to the Ronald Lawson Research Files for the Tenant Movement in New York City TAM.214
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Research Files (box 14): Includes Queens Presidents' Council; Parkchester Tenants Association; Riverdale Park Tenants Association; West Side Tenants Union
  - Riverdale Park Tenants Association - 700, Sep 23, 1973, Oct 19, 1973, undated (Box 14, Folder 57)
  - Riverdale Park Tenants Association - 800, undated (Box 14, Folder 58)
  - Riverdale Park Tenants Association - 900, undated (Box 14, Folder 59)
  - West Side Tenants Union, Sep 27, 1973-May 22, 1974, Jun 2, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 60)
  - (West Side Tenants Union): 75 East End Avenue, 755 West End - Student Papers, May 22, 1973, undated (Box 14, Folder 61)
  - West Side Tenants Union, Dec 19, 1972-Dec 28, 1976, undated (Box 14, Folder 62)
  - West Side Tenants Union - Meeting Notes, Sep 27, 1973-May 22, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 63)
  - West Side Tenants Union - Meeting Notes, Sep 27, 1973-May 22, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 64)
  - West Side Tenants Union - 012 and Leaders, Sep 27, 1973-May 21, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 65)
  - West Side Tenants Union - 100, Sep 27, 1973, undated (Box 14, Folder 66)
  - West Side Tenants Union - 200, Sep 27, 1973, undated (Box 14, Folder 67)
  - West Side Tenants Union - 300, Oct 4, 1973-May 21, 1974, undated (Box 14, Folder 68)
  - West Side Tenants Union - 400, undated (Box 14, Folder 69)
  - West Side Tenants Union - 500, undated (Box 14, Folder 70)
  - West Side Tenants Union - 600, undated (Box 14, Folder 71)
  - West Side Tenants Union - 700, undated (Box 14, Folder 72)
  - West Side Tenants Union - 800, undated (Box 14, Folder 73)
  - West Side Tenants Union - 900, undated (Box 14, Folder 74)
  - West Side Tenants Union - Student Papers, Oct 1972, Jun 1, 1976, undated (Box 14, Folder 75)
  - Flatbush Tenants Council - 500, Oct 25, 1973-Feb 19, 1974, undated (Box 14, Folder 76)
  - Flatbush Tenants Council - 600, Jan 1974-May 15, 1974, undated (Box 14, Folder 77)
  - Flatbush Tenants Council - 700, Nov 7, 1973-Feb 26, 1974, undated (Box 14, Folder 78)
  - Flatbush Tenants Council - 800, Dec 15, 1973-May 15, 1974, undated (Box 14, Folder 79)
  - Flatbush Tenants Council - 900, Feb 15, 1974-May 15, 1974, undated (Box 14, Folder 76, Folder 80)
- Research Files (box 15): Includes Adopt-A-Building; Los Sures; Longwood Community Management Corporation; Flatbush Tenants Council
  - Adopt-A-Building - Student Papers, Studies, Dec 14, 1973-Oct 31, 1979, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Adopt-A-Building - "Tenant Organizing and Management: A Case Study Prepared for the Office of Neighborhood Development Department of Housing and Urban Development", Feb 1979 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Adopt-A-Building, Oct 2, 1973-Jan 21, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Adopt-A-Building, Nov 14, 1969-Jul 1974 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Adopt-A-Building - Student Papers, Dec 12, 1975-Fall 1976, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Adopt-A-Building - Meeting Notes, Sep 25, 1973-Apr 23, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Adopt-A-Building - Meeting Notes, Sep 25, 1973-Apr 23, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Adopt-A-Building - 024 and Leaders, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Adopt-A-Building - 100: Ecology, Sep 25, 1973-Dec 6, 1973, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Adopt-A-Building - 200: Beginnings and History, Dec 13, 1973-Apr 23, 1974, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Adopt-A-Building - 300: Structure and Finances, Sep 25, 1973-Jan 24, 1974, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Adopt-A-Building - 400: Goals and Tactics, Oct 11, 1973, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Adopt-A-Building - 500: Leaders and Key Personnel, Sep 25, 1973-Nov 3, 1973, undated (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Adopt-A-Building - 600: Membership and Mobilization, Oct 11, 1973-Feb 14, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Adopt-A-Building - 700: The Observer and the Group, Sep 25, 1973-Feb 14, 1974, undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Adopt-A-Building - 900: Related Institutions, Dec 6, 1973, undated (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Adopt-A-Building - "A Portrait of Loisaida", Jun 1978 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Los Sures, undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Los Sures - Henry Lanier Research, Nov 28, 19[73]-Jun 12, 1974, undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Los Sures, Aug 1980-Sep 1980 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Los Sures - Southside United Housing Development Fund Corp., Mar 28, 1971-Apr 29, 1975, undated (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Los Sures - Mongraph by R. Johnson, undated (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - (Los Sures) - Student Paper: Auslander, Andrew. "Factors Involving Subjective Reality and Consciousness as Related to the Poor of Williamburg's Southside in the Field of Housing.", Fall 1974 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Los Sures - Student Papers, Dec 18, 1975, Jun 2, 1976, undated (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Los Sures - Meeting Notes, Jan 7, 1974-Mar 20, 1974, undated (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Los Sures - Meeting Notes, Nov 28, 19[73]-May 9, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Los Sures - 028 and Leaders, Sep 18, 1973, Feb 19, 1974, undated (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Los Sures - 100, Nov 28, 19[73], Jan 7, 1974, undated (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Los Sures - 200, undated (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Los Sures - 300, undated (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Los Sures - 400, Nov 28, 19[73], Dec 17, 1973, undated (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Los Sures - 500, Feb 19, 1974-May 9, 1974, undated (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Los Sures - 600, undated (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Los Sures - 700, Dec 17, 1973, Mar 1974, undated (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Los Sures-800, Mar 20, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Los Sures - 900, undated (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - People's Development Corporation, Mar 30, 1977-1979 (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Longwood Community Management Corporation, Jan 30, 1974-Mar 18, 1974, undated (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Longwood Community Management Corporation - Monograph by R. Johnson, undated (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Longwood Community Management Corporation - Meeting Notes, Jan 30, 1974-Mar 18, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - Longwood Community Management Corporation - Meeting Notes, Jan 30, 1974-Apr 24, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 41)
  - Longwood Community Management Corporation - 036 and Leaders, Jan 30, 1974, undated (Box 15, Folder 42)
  - Longwood Community Management Corporation - 100, Jan 30, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 43)
  - Longwood Community Management Corporation - 200, Feb 28, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 44)
  - Longwood Community Management Corporation - 300, Feb 28,1974, undated (Box 15, Folder 45)
  - Longwood Community Management Corporation - 400, Jan 30, 1974, undated (Box 15, Folder 46)
  - Longwood Community Management Corporation - 500, Jan 30, 1974, Feb 28, 1974, undated (Box 15, Folder 47)
  - Longwood Community Management Corporation - 600, undated (Box 15, Folder 48)
  - Longwood Community Management Corporation - 700, Mar 18, 1974, Apr 24, 1974, undated (Box 15, Folder 49)
  - Longwood Community Management Corporation - 900, Feb, 28, 1974-Apr 24, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 50)
  - Longwood Community Management Corporation, Apr 24, 1974, undated (Box 15, Folder 51)
  - Flatbush Tenants Council - Meeting Notes, Sep 20, 1973-May 15, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 52)
  - Flatbush Tenants Council - Meeting Notes, Sep 20, 1973-May 15, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 53)
  - Flatbush Tenants Council - 016 and Leaders, Sep 20, 1973, undated (Box 15, Folder 54)
  - Flatbush Tenants Council - 100 (and Student Paper), Jan 16, 1974-May 21, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 55)
  - Flatbush Tenants Council - 200, undated (Box 15, Folder 56)
  - Flatbush Tenants Council - 300, Sep 20, 1973-Feb 19, 1974, undated (Box 15, Folder 57)
  - Flatbush Tenants Council - 400, Sep 20, 1973-May 15, 1974, undated (Box 15, Folder 58)
- Research Files (box 16): Includes Research Grant Applications and Publishing Correspondence
  - Applications for Funding - "Seventh Day Adventists in Conflict: A Sociological Explanation", "The Impact of Tenant Activism upon the Social Process of Housing Abandonment.", Feb 27, 1977-Oct 7, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Applications for Funding - "Seventh Day Adventists in Conflict: A Sociological Explanation", "The Impact of Tenant Activism upon the Social Process of Housing Abandonment.", Feb 27, 1977-Oct 7, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Tenant Mobilization - Publication Correspondence and Manuscript, Sep 16, 1982, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Applications for Funding - "The Impact of Tenant Activism upon the Social Process of Building Abandonment", Oct 24, 1977-1981, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - "Tenant Mobilization and its Consequences" - Proposals, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Proposal - Materials, undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Center for Policy Research, Inc. - Grant, Apr 18, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Tenant Leader Questionnaires, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - N.I.M.H. Proposal, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Grant Application - "Tenant Organizations: Mobilization and Consequences", May 31, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - "The Tenant Organization: A Strategic Research Site" - Draft, undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Application for Continuation Grant - N.I.M.H., Mar 29, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Application for Continuation Grant - N.I.M.H., Mar 1975 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence to Ronald Lawson, Oct 15, 1973-Nov 29, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Columbia University: Bureau of Applied Social Research - Community Leadership Study: NYC Neighborhood Project, Sep 1973 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Publications, Manuscripts, Papers - Tenant Movement, 1972-1983, undated (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Schneider, Kathleen. "Tenant Mobilization Without Housing Reform.", July 1975, undated (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Tenant Organization Studies, undated (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - "The Urban Housing Problem", undated (Box 16, Folder 19)
- Research Files (box 17): Includes Case Studies; Non-New York City Tenant Organizations; Scholarly Articles by Others
  - Neighborhood Data, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Neighborhood - Complete Codebook, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Neighborhood Codebook, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Strategic Choices, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Homes Leadership, Oct 17, 1979-Nov 8, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Tenant Organization Questionnaire Codebook, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Interviews Identification Numbers - Computer Codes: (Tenant Organizations, Leaders/Organizers, BOs), undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Content Analysis - (Tenant Movement Study: Newspaper Coverage of Housing Issues and Tenant Movement), undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Case Studies - RBJ: 2-196, Sep 25, 1973-Mar 18, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Case Studies - RBJ: 202-286, Mar 18, 1974-May 9, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Case Studies - TD: 1-13 (Flatbush Tenants' Council: Tri-Monthly Meeting; Riverdale Park Tenant Committee; Lincoln Towers Tenant Association), Sep 20, 1973-Sep 27, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Case Studies - GB: 1-25 (Citywide Save Our Homes, undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Case Studies - AN: 1-139, Oct 19, 1973Jun 3, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Case Studies - McL: 1-184, Sep 21, 1973-Mar 11, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Johnson, Reuben. "Variables, Hypotheses, and Generalizations.", undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Tenant Leader Questionnaires, Building Organization Codebook, undated (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Building Organization Codebooks, undated (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - St. Louis - (Housing Authority, Tenants), 1973-Jun 5, 1974, undated (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - International Union of Tenants, Apr 4, 1973-Oct 6, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - National Tenants Organization, Inc. (N.T.O.), Dec 1971-Oct 30, 1975, undated (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - National Tenants Organization Information Services, Jun 15, 1972-Jan 1975, undated (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Birmingham Tenants Organization, undated (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Nationwide Tenant Organizations, Associations, Leaders, Contacts, undated (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Other Places, USA, 1974-1976, undated (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Legislation, undated (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - N.Y.C. Area Poverty Maps, undated (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Barron, Richard. "St. Louis Tenant Management Corporations Bringing Major Transformation of Public Housing." Journal of Housing, Vol. 31, No. 6, pp 263-269., Jun 1974 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Community Profiles, Jan 1973-Mar 1973 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Alinsky, Saul. "Community Analysis and Organization." American Journal of Sociology, Vol. 46. pp 797-808., undated (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Stone, Michael. "Housing, Mortgages, and the State." pp 25-36., undated (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Allen, Richard C.. "Evictions Under The 1970 Massachusetts Rent Control Act.", Apr 26, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Starr, Roger. "The Lesson of Forest Hills." pp 45-49., undated (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Stretton, Hugh. "Capital Mistakes." C. Bell, S Encel (eds). Inside The Whale. Perpamon., 1978 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Edel, Matthew. "The New York Crisis as Economic History.", undated (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - "The Recurrent Crisis of London: Anti-Report on the Property Developers.", undated (Box 17, Folder 35)
- Research Files (box 18): Includes International Tenant Activism, including Tenants Union of Victoria (Australia)
  - West Side Tenants Union - Press Coverage (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Squatter - London, Aug 26, 1973, Nov 3, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - International Union of Tenants, 1974-Aug 25, 1975, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Continental Europe (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Great Britain (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Canada - "L'Habitation et Les Citoyen/Housing and People" (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - San Francisco Tenants Movement (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Downtown Welfare Advocacy Center (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Williamsburg - Student Paper, Fall 1974 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - New York State Tenants Coalition; Chicago, Apr 1975; Oct 17, 1975-Oct 19, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Australian Tenants - Tenants Union of Victoria: Questionnaire, Chapter 3-7, undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Australian Tenants - Tenants Union of Victoria: Chapter 8-10, "Materials and Notes on Landlord/Tenant Relations", undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Australian Tenants - Tenants Union of Victoria (Box 18, Folder 13)
- Research Files (box 19): Includes Center for Tenants Rights; Inwood Tenants Association; Lincoln Towers Tenant Association
  - Carnegie Hill Neighbors - 021 and Leaders, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Center for Tenants Rights, Nov 1973-May 10, 1974, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Center for Tenants Rights - Student Papers, Oct 15, 1973-Nov 12, 1973, undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Center for Tenants Rights - 0101 and Leaders, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Center for Tenants Rights - 200, Aug 1973 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Center for Tenants Rights - 300, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Center for Tenants Rights - 400, Aug 1973, undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Center for Tenants Rights - 600, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Center for Tenants Rights - 800, Aug 1973, undated (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Center for Tenants Rights - 900, undated (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Center for Tenants Rights - Interview Notes, Aug 1973 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Center for Tenants Rights - Interview Notes, Aug 1973 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Center for Tenants Rights - Extra Sheets, Aug 1973, undated (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Chelsea Action Center - Student Paper, Apr 10, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Coalition on Housing in Washington Heights, Jul 25, 1973, undated (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Coalition for Human Housing - Student Papers, Feb 22, 1972-Apr 24, 1972, undated (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Coalition of Riverside Tenant Associations (C.O.R.T.A.) - Student Papers, undated (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Coalition of Riverside Tenant Associations (C.O.R.T.A.) - Clippings, undated (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Cooper Square, Aug 1969-Nov 8, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Cooper Square, Nov 8, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Cooper Square - Student Papers, Nov 1, 1972-Jan 18, 1973, undated (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Dorchester Towers Tenants Council, Inc., Oct 1974-Feb 1978 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - East 49th Street Tenants Group, Apr 1973 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - East 87th Block Association - Student Paper, Mar 1973-Sum 1973, undated (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - East Harlem Tenant Council - Student Paper, undated (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - East Harlem Tenants Council - Student Paper, Fall 1974 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - East Side Residential Association, undated (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - East Side Residential Association - 0013 and Leaders, undated (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - 15 Churches United for a Better East Side, Jan 1972-Jun 1974 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Florence Nightingale Save-Our-Homes Committee, Sep 7, 1973-Jan 11, 1974, undated (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Florence Nightingale Save-Our-Homes - 005 and Leaders, undated (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Franklin Plaza, Mar 1973-Aug 1973 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Harlem Tenants Union - 032 and Leaders, Aug 1973-Aug 21, 1975, undated (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - "Housing Conservation Coordinators - Aged Participation" - Student Paper, Mar 19, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Housing Conservation Coordinators, Clinton - Student Papers, undated (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Housing Conservation Coordinators - Student Papers, Spr 1975-Fall 1976, undated (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Housing Conservation Coordinators - Student Paper, Fall 1975 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Housing Conservation Coordinators - Student Papers, Fall 1975, Jun 4, 1976, undated (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Housing Conservation Coordinators, Feb 27, 1975, Apr 20, 1976, undated (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Housing Conservation Coordinators - Clippings, undated (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - Hudson Towers Tenant Association - Student Papers, Dec 28, 1973, undated (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - Inwood Tenants Association, Sep 23, 1973-May 28, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - Inwood Tenants Association - Meeting Notes, Sep 23, 1973-May 28, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 43)
  - Inwood Tenants Association, Mar 21, 1972-May 28, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 44)
  - Inwood Tenants Association - 085 and Leaders, Nov 18, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 45)
  - Inwood Tenants Association - 100, May 28, 1974, undated (Box 19, Folder 46)
  - Inwood Tenants Association - 200, Sep 23, 1973, undated (Box 19, Folder 47)
  - Inwood Tenants Association - 300, May 28, 1974, undated (Box 19, Folder 48)
  - Inwood Tenants Association - 400, Sep 23, 1973, May 28, 1974, undated (Box 19, Folder 49)
  - Inwood Tenants Association - 500, May 28, 1974, undated (Box 19, Folder 50)
  - Inwood Tenants Association - 600, Nov 18, 1973, undated (Box 19, Folder 51)
  - Inwood Tenants Association - 700, undated (Box 19, Folder 52)
  - Inwood Tenants Association - Extra Sheets, Sep 23, 1973, Nov 18, 1973, undated (Box 19, Folder 53)
  - Lenox Hill Neighborhood Association, 1973-1974, undated (Box 19, Folder 54)
  - Lenox Hill Neighborhood Association - 0021 and Leaders, undated (Box 19, Folder 55)
  - Lenox Hill Neighborhood Association, undated (Box 19, Folder 56)
  - Lincoln Tower Tenant Association, Apr 16, 1973-Apr 4, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 57)
  - Lincoln Tower Tenant Association, Sep 27, 1973, Apr 4, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 58)
  - Lincoln Towers Tenant Association, Sep 27, 1973, Apr 4, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 59)
  - Lincoln Towers Tenant Association - 014 and Leaders, undated (Box 19, Folder 60)
  - Lincoln Towers Tenant Association - 100: Ecology, Sep 27, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 61)
  - Lincoln Towers Tenant Association - 200: Beginnings and History, undated (Box 19, Folder 62)
  - Lincoln Towers Tenant Association - 300: Structure and Finances, Sep 27, 1973, undated (Box 19, Folder 63)
  - Lincoln Towers Tenant Association - 400: Goals and Tactics, undated (Box 19, Folder 64)
  - Lincoln Towers Tenant Association - 500: Leaders and Key Personnel, undated (Box 19, Folder 65)
  - Lincoln Towers Tenant Association - 600, undated (Box 19, Folder 66)
  - Lincoln Towers Tenant Association - Extra Copies and Sheets, Sep 27, 1973, Apr 4, 1974, undated (Box 19, Folder 67)
  - Lindley House Tenant Association - Student Paper, Fall 1973 (Box 19, Folder 68)
  - Lower East Side: Its's Time - Student Paper, undated (Box 19, Folder 69)
  - Manhattanville Development Center - Student Paper, undated (Box 19, Folder 70)
  - Manhattan Valley Development Corporation - Student Papers, Jan 1978, undated (Box 19, Folder 71)
- Research Files (box 20): Includes Mitchell-Lama; Stuyvesant Town; West Side Urban Renewal Area (Box 20)
  - Franklin Plaza Cooperative in East Harlem (Mitchell-Lama), Oct 1973-Jun 1975 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Jefferson Towers Tenants' Advisory Council (Mitchell-Lama)- Student Paper, May 21, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Metro North Association - Student Paper, 1964-Jan 8, 1973, undated (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Mitchell-Lama - Meeting Notes, Apr 17, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Mitchell-Lama - 045 and Leaders, Nov 15, 1973, Apr 17, 1974, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Mitchell-Lama - 400, Apr 17, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Mitchell-Lama - 600, Apr 17, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Mitchell-Lama - Tenant Questionnaires, undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Mitchell-Lama - Student Paper, Jun 1976 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Mitchell-Lama, Jul 8, 1973-Dec 7, 1974, undated (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Mobilization for Youth - Student Papers, Dec 18, 1975, Jun 2, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Morningside Tenants Council, undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Morningside Renewal Council, Apr 25, 1975-Jun 24, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Mount Sinai - Student Papers, Spr 1973, undated (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Neighborhood Board 3, Jun 1974 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Neighborhood Board 5, undated (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Neighborhood Save Our Home - Student Paper, Feb 22, 1972-May 12, 1972, undated (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Place (Clinton Midtown Association) - Student Paper, May 24, 1974 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Project FIND, May 1975 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Pueblo Nuevo, undated (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Renigades Housing Movement, undated (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Reporte de Ocupacion, Jul 1974 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Roosevelt Hospital - 082 and Leaders, undated (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Rose Hill Farm Neighborhood Association - Student Paper, Dec 28, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Save Our Neighborhood - Student Paper, 1968-Sep 1973, undated (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Save Our Neighborhood - Student Papers, Mar 17, 1972-Jan 2, 1974, undated (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Stryckers' Bay Neighborhood Council - Student Papers, Sep 25, 1973-Dec 5, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Stuyesant Town Tenants Association, undated (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Stuyevesant Town Tenants Association - Student Papers, Jan 24, 1972-Dec 25, 1974, undated (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Tudor City Association, Inc., Jan 4, 1974, undated (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Tudor City Tenants Association, Inc. - Student Papers, Jan 2, 1974, undated (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Two Bridges Neighborhood Council - Student Paper, Fall 1974 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Two Bridges We Won't Cross, undated (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Two Bridges We Won't Move Committee - Student Papers, Jan 3, 1973-Jan 2, 1974, undated (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - United Block Association 68 East 131st Street. "How To Form A Block Association.", undated (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Washington Heights Tenants Association - Student Papers, Jun 10, 1970-Mar 1, 1976, undated (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - West Harlem Community Organization - Student Papers, Jun 2, 1976, undated (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - West Side Manor Tenants Association - Student Paper, undated (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - Westsiders United, 1977, Mar 1978, undated (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - West Side Urban Renewal - 009 and Leaders, Nov 15, 1973, undated (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - West Side Urban Renewal Area, Oct 25, 1973, undated (Box 20, Folder 41)
  - West Village Committee and Neighborhood Association - Student Paper, 1973-Jan 2, 1974, undated (Box 20, Folder 42)